Well, this is exciting. We're in cursor.
We're going to do some vibe coding. So,
first up, just just to tell you some
shortcut keys, which are good to know.
Um, on uh to to flip in and out the the
side bar on the left, the file system.
On a Mac, it's commandB. On a PC, it's
controlB. So, if you press that a couple
of times, look at that. You'll see that
it's coming in and out. It also uh it
mentions that just just here as well. Uh
and uh for the right hand bar over here
which has the agent chat on a Mac it's
command option B and on a PC it's
control option B. So let me do that a
few times. There you go. You see? So
that's that's something uh nice to get
used to. So that's how you can bring in
and out the two different screens if
they're not there right now. Okay,
that's oriented you. Now we're going to
look at this repo and see what files
we've got. Okay. Well, I have news for
you. We don't have a lot of files. In
fact, we've only got one file in this
repo. It was a lot of palava for one
file cloning this repo. I could have
just given you this file, but here it
is. It is, of course, the file called
agents.md,
which is the file that is going to be
loaded in by default into the the the
agents memory when we set it going. And
if I click on it, we can have a look at
it. And it's written in markdown, which
means that it's got all the familiar
markdown tags. That's a main heading.
That's a secondary heading. It's got
different sections. It's got bulleted
lists and numbered lists with various
sections. You can also rightclick on the
file and say open preview. And if you do
that, you see it in a sort of formatted
way. And this is if you if you will,
this is the way that the agent sees it
because it sees markdown and it
interprets it as actually being the
headings that it is. So this is really
looking at it the way the agent will see
it. Okay. And I wrote this agents.mmd. I
didn't generate it. I hand wrote it. I
cranked it out. And I'm going to take
you through it right now. So the idea of
this project is to try and build a
simple project management application.
Something which has like a camban board
like you have in in in Jira or in Trello
or products like that. If you're not
familiar with them, Google it and you'll
see what I mean. And so we want one of
these things. It's like like a like a
sort of note board with cards that you
can move between them. So I've got the
first section is called business
requirements of the canban project. We
want an MVP, a minimum viable product, a
prototype if you will of a canban style
project management application as a web
app. It should only have one board.
Let's keep it simple. Always start
simple. Have fixed five columns that can
be renamed. Each card will have a title
and details only. We want a drag and
drop interface to move cards between
columns. Okay, so that's not so simple,
but we need something that's going to be
cool. You're going to be able to add a
card, uh, delete an existing card, but
no more functionality than that. No
archive, no search and filter. Keep it
simple. The priority is a slick,
professional, gorgeous UI, very simple
features, and it should open with dummy
data. There are the business
requirements. They're laid out. The
sorts of tricks to doing a good
agents.md. You want to lay things out to
be precise. You don't want to be
ambiguous. You want to be very clear to
generally focus on the positives. But
I've got a couple of negatives in there,
but that's okay. Generally, focus on on
being sort of assertive and clear and
and do it in a way that means that it's
absolutely obvious what needs to be
built. And I know what you're thinking.
You're thinking, "But but Ed, when in
real world when we're building big
projects, they're much more complicated
than this." And I say patience,
patience. We've got three weeks
together. There'll be time to get more
complicated. We want to start with
something neat. Okay. So this is is the
requirements and by the way you should
feel free to change this if you want to
have something different if you want to
see what get the same as me or similar
to me then stick with this but feel free
to change it the technical details so we
I am going to try and tell it how I
wanted to build it a bit I want it to be
a NexJS app I want it to use that
technology I want it to be in a
subdirectory called front end so there
can be a subdirectory here called front
end no persistence nothing being saved
here no user login or anything like
that. Tell it to use popular libraries
as simple as possible but with an
elegant UI. There's you might say, isn't
that some repetition with the previous
section? There's no harm in repetition
with these things, particularly for the
really important points you want to
make. Be be clear. It's fine to repeat
yourself. Okay. Next up, I've got a
color scheme. These are my favorite
colors that I use for my my various
decks. So, I just pasted it in here. I
had it to hand. You can change this up.
Use your own or just take it out. Let
let it come up with its own color
scheme. You don't need to to do this if
you don't wish. And then I got a
strategy section. Write a plan with
success criteria for each phase to be
checked off. Include project
scaffolding, rigorous unit testing. Then
execute the plan. Then carry out
extensive integration testing with
playright or similar fixing defects.
Only completes when the MVP is finished
and tested with the server running and
ready for the user. I use many of these
same kinds of things often. So, so this
is something that's that's fairly
boilerplate. It's always good to lay it
out this way. Increasingly, it's less
necessary to say things like this
because this kind of strategy is the
kind of default strategy that most of
these agentic AIs are now following more
and more closely. But there's no harm in
putting it in here. And I found this was
kind of helpful. So, I've kept it in.
And then at the end, coding standards.
These three are just three that that I
like to use. similar kind of thing.
Actually, I I used to use a lot more
than this. I used to use this a lot, but
but it's becoming increasingly less
necessary to say this because LLMs are
starting to get the joke, but I say use
latest versions of libraries, idiomatic
approaches as of today. I don't need to
tell it the date. I need to hardcode the
date because they've got access to that,
but I just remind it to to be cognizant
that it needs to look at the latest
versions. Keep it simple. Never
overengineer. Always simplify. No
unnecessary defensive programming, no
extra features, focus on simplicity.
Again, it's less necessary to say it
now, but I still it's I still see it
frequently over complicating and I feel
like you can't stress this too much. So,
I do be concise. Keep read me minimal,
important. No emojis ever. Like to put
that in there because these things love
to make emojis and emojis are a pain and
they just get in the way. And and maybe
you like emojis, in which case you can
take this out and and let it let it go
to town. But uh I I find it thoroughly
tiresome and and it also does actually
cause some breaks sometimes with with
Windows PCs. So So I like to say no no
emojis. As I say, you you can you can
add on more and you feel free to add on
some of your your own pet peeves to get
this right. And it's something that that
can be a sort of living breathing
document for you of the the coding
stands you like. And we'll find out
later how you can have things like this
in a more central place where they're
used for all of your projects. Now, you
might be thinking, "Okay, Ed, but you
just shown us this file, but don't don't
we have to learn how to write these
kinds of things ourselves?" And the
answer is, "Well, yes, but to be honest,
you can always just start with what I've
got here as a starting point, or you can
just write one yourself from scratch. It
actually honestly doesn't matter that
much. You got to get into the habit of
being very specific and simple about
what you want. You don't need to give it
technical details. It can figure that
out itself. You don't need to give a
color scheme. You don't need to give it
the strategy, but you could just copy
exactly what I've got here. And the
coding standards again, you could start
with exactly what I've got. You could
add to them over during this course,
we're going to be experimenting with
different kinds of of of standards and
rules that we will give these LLMs. So,
this is something which you can you can
experiment with. You can also begin with
something much more minimal, run it, see
what you get, and then delete everything
that it's built, and rewrite this to be
something that's more precise and and
accounts for where it went wrong when it
was just just allowed to do whatever it
wants. That's a very effective
technique, working iteratively like
that. So, these are all great ways to
build your agents.mmd
and and uh yeah, honestly, you can you
can always just begin with what I have
here and just updating the requirements
to be what you want. And now I'd like
you to bring up the cursor settings. You
can get to it from the settings menu or
on a PC, control shiftJ. On a Mac,
command shiftJ. Here it is. Go to
agents. Scroll down to the um auto run
section. And this is now your choice. If
you know, if you have some sense of what
you're doing, you're familiar with the
risks, you can do this on yolo mode. Run
everything unsandboxed as we did for
instant. Now, this is a very low risk.
The project we're about to do is low
risk, and personally, I'm happy doing
this. I know what's happening. I can
kick it off. I'll walk away. It's a risk
I'm comfortable with. But it's a
personal preference. If you're not
entirely sure about what's going on and
what you're signing up for, then please
leave it auto run in sandbox or even ask
every time. And that way you'll see what
it's doing at each step, the files it's
creating. You will say approve and you
can keep doing that. And you can keep
doing that until you get more
comfortable with what's happening. And
then you can move it into run everything
sand unsandbox to yolo mode when you're
ready. But I'm I'm here to take some
risks. So I'm going with that from the
get-go. Okay, there we go.